<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Adventures in Learning</title>
    <link href="http://paulnorthup.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://paulnorthup.com" />
    <updated>2020-04-14T11:33:59-04:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Paul Northup</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://paulnorthup.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Rear subframe modifications</title>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Northup</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://paulnorthup.com/frame-modifications.html"/>
        <id>http://paulnorthup.com/frame-modifications.html</id>
            <category term="Motorcycle"/>
            <category term="KZ550"/>

        <updated>2020-04-14T11:26:24-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I started by cutting the back of the rear subframe off and welding on a new hoop to give a nice clean rounded "butt" to the bike. I realized there was a problem with the new hoop when I mocked up a seat with some&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>I started by cutting the back of the rear subframe off and welding on a new hoop to give a nice clean rounded "butt" to the bike.</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><img src="http://paulnorthup.com/media/posts/1/rear-hoop.jpg" alt="New hoop welded on" width="580" height="600">
<figcaption >New hoop welded on</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>I realized there was a problem with the new hoop when I mocked up a seat with some carpet foam. I figured a standard size café/brat seat would look pretty good, so I went with ~2" of foam, but it looked horrible. The angle of the rear subframe on the LTD model of a KZ550 is steep to support a two-up "King and Queen" seat, not the style I was looking for.</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><img src="http://paulnorthup.com/media/posts/1/ugly-seat.JPG" alt="" width="600" height="450">
<figcaption >Here is the ugly seat, with the tire mocked up for positioning. The ramp is longer than the flat section... yuck.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>I spent some time thinking about the seat frame, mocking up different seat options with cardboard, etc. After a while, I got so frustrated with making no progress I cut off the hoop, chopped the rest of the rear seat frame off, and welded the hoop back on. this gave me a much more aggressive look, and the proportions really started to come together.</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><img src="http://paulnorthup.com/media/posts/1/short-seat.JPG" alt="" width="2072" height="1554">
<figcaption >If life gives you subframe lemons, chop them right out and don't worry about 'em.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Along with the subframe work, I grinded off the rest of the frame tabs I wasn't going to use and bent the old rear shock mount supports around the new hoop to keep the original lines of the bike. Happy with the progress so far.<br><br></p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
